Guide to the Jean-François Bory Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Audiovisual Works, 1957-2013; Series II; 6; 10 boxes + 1 film reel
  - Son@rt Productions, 1998-2013
    - Media
      - Palestine, Charlemagne. Hommage à Faquir Pandit Pran Nath, Concert le 16 mars 1997 (son@rt 007), 1999; 1 (Box 30)
      - Seuphor, Michel. Entretien: Jacques Donguy, Michel Mousseau (son@rt 007), 1999; 1 (Box 30)
      - Revue littéraire sonore (son@rt 008), 1999; 2 (Box 30)
      - McLuhan, Marshall. The Medium is the Massage (son@rt 009), 1999; 1 (Box 30)
      - Filliou, Robert. Le réseau éternel, Entretien avec Jacques Donguy (son@rt 10), 1999; 1 (Box 30)
      - Autobiographie vocale de Le Corbusier enregistrée deux mois avant sa mort (son@rt 011), 1999; 1 (Box 30)
      - Altagor. Conférence, 1950, Discours Absolu, extraits, 1960, Entretien, 1979 (son@rt 013), [2000]; 1 (Box 30)
      - Words around the world, Millenium International (son@rt 014), 2000; 1 (Box 30)
      - Quand j'étais nié, Conférence à Marseille le 25 septembre 1999 (son@rt 015), 2000; 1 (Box 30)
      - 70 minutes de poésie en l'an 2000 (son@rt 016), 1 (Box 30)
      - Remix, Bosons de Jauge, Jacques Donguy (son@rt 017), 2000; 1 (Box 30)
      - Colloque de Cerisy (son@rt 018), 2000; 1 (Box 30)
      - Isou, Isidore and Lemaître, Maurice. Rituel somptueux pour la sélection des espèces (son@rt 019), 2001; 1 (Box 30)
      - Soirées Olympic Café APEGAC (son@rt 020), 2001; 1 (Box 30)
      - International (son@rt 021), 2001; 1 (Box 30)
      - Donguy, Jacques. Poésie visuelle sonore, École des Beaux-Arts de Metz (son@rt 023), 2001; 1 (Box 30)
      - Mühl, Otto. Psychomotorik (son@rt 024), 2002; 1 (Box 30)
      - Beurard-Valdoye, Patrick. Flux (son@rt 025), 2002; 1 (Box 30)
      - «Les disants» du cipM (son@rt 026), 2002; 1 (Box 30)
      - Lambert, Jean-Clarence. Code, Poésie expérimentale 1953-1973 (son@rt 027), 2002; 1 (Box 30)
      - Option libertaire, Paul Virilio, Mouvement anomiste, 1968-69, Perspectives des luttes révolutionnaires (son@rt 028), 2002; 1 (Box 30)
      - Bory, Jean-François. SAGA (son@rt 029), 2002; 1 (Box 31)
      - Ferlinghetti, Lawrence. History of the Airplane, To the Oracle at Delphi (son@rt 030), 2002; 1 (Box 30)
      - Anthologie 2002 (son@rt 031), 1 (Box 30)
      - Donguy, Jacques. Phares Gamma (son@rt 033), 2002; 1 (Box 30)
      - Dufrêne, François (son@rt 034), 2003; 1 (Box 30)
      - Étant donnés… Duchamp, dernier délai (son@rt 035), 2003; 1 (Box 31)
      - Anthologie sonore 2003 (son@rt 036), 1 (Box 30)
      - Lectures performances, une anthologie (son@rt 037), 2003; 1 (Box 31)
      - Anthologie Jacques Donguy (son@rt 039), 2004; 1 (Box 31)
      - Anthologie 2004 (son@rt 040), 1 (Box 30)
      - Bory, Jean-François. Quant au livre (son@rt 041), 2004; 1 (Box 31)
      - Le Batteur du boléro, Un film de Jean-François Bory (son@rt 041), [2005?]; 1 (Box 31)
      - Chopin, Henri. Performances de poésie sonore (son@rt 045), 2006; 1 (Box 31)
      - Anthologie 2006 II, poésie numérique et documents historiques (son@rt 047), 1 (Box 31)
      - Kac, Eduardo. Holopoèmes, poèmes minitel, poèmes numériques, biopoèmes (son@rt 048), 2006; 1 (Box 31)
      - Brunet, Étienne and Donguy, Jacques. Live in São Paulo (son@rt 049), 2009; 1 (Box 30)
      - L'Humidité: no.1-25 & maquette du no.26 jamais publié (son@rt 050), [2010]; 1 (Box 39)
      - Campos, Augusto de. Poésie est risque (son@rt 051), 2011; 1 (Box 31)
      - Hommage à Isidore Isou (son@rt 052), 2011; 1 (Box 31)
  - SAGA Film Archives, 1968
    Photographs of the film set appear first under the heading Files, followed by reel-to-reel and cassette tapes under the heading Media.
    - Files
      - Photographs of set, undated (Box 19, Folder 184)
      - Photocopies of original reel container labels, undated (Box 19, Folder 185)
    - Media
      - "Son SAGA", 1968; 1 (Box 32, Item barcode 39002091246547)
        Restricted fragile material. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
      - Small film reels and fragments, undated; 19 (Box 34 (Cold storage))
      - Unique copy of film in Kodak Plus X, 1968; 1 (Box 35 (Cold storage))
  - Quant au Livre Film Archives, 1998-2007
    Background materials to the film appear first under the heading Files, followed by audiovisual and electronic media listed alphabetically under the heading Media.
    - Files
      - Background material, undated (Box 19, Folder 186-188)
      - Holograph notebook, undated (Box 19, Folder 189)
      - Photographs of set, 2003-2004 (Box 19, Folder 190-194)
    - Media
      Boxes 32-33 (audiovisual): Restricted fragile material. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
      Boxes 37-38 (computer media): Restricted fragile material. Reference copies of electronic files may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
      - "Aimer, bonne version 07", undated; 1 (Box 33, Item barcode 39002091246232)
        1'22
      - "Aimer, c'est... 07 1ere version mauvaise", undated; 1 (Box 33, Item barcode 39002091246257)
      - "3 Babil", undated; 1 (Box 37)
      - "Le battela di carta, 07", undated; 1 (Box 33, Item barcode 39002091246166)
      - "Bonne version allégée de Passageno" (empty case), 2006; Empty MiniDV container (Box 33)
      - "Bruits enfant [...] Babils", undated; 1 (Box 32)
      - "Capitulation Hiro-Hito", undated; 1 (Box 37)
      - "Capitulation Hiro-Hito", undated; 1 (Box 32)
      - "Caroline Deseille - Les couleurs", 2003; 1 (Box 37)
      - "Cris d'enfant qui naît", undated; 1 (Box 37)
      - "Dada & Cie, (corrigé) son@rt, Bon DV", 2005 October 15; 1 (Box 33, Item barcode 39002091246265)
      - "Duchamp fin", undated; 1 (Box 32)
      - "Film, photos + texte", undated; 1 (Box 37)
      - "Film voix vieilles", 2004 April 4; 1 (Box 32, Item barcode 39002091246539)
      - "Fiona voix petite fille", undated; 1 (Box 32)
      - "Galaxias avec musique", undated; 1 (Box 32)
      - "Galaxias (lu par moi) le texte seul", undated; 1 (Box 37)
      - "Galaxie le texte seul", undated; 1 (Box 32)
      - "Générique Son@rt", undated; 1 (Box 37)
      - "Infans gazouilli", undated; 1 (Box 37)
      - "La Marseillaise, master", 2009; 1 (Box 33, Item barcode 39002091246158)
      - "Marseilles carnets d'un soir", 2007, 2008; 1 (Box 33, Item barcode 39002091246174)
        12'
      - [Master copy], 2004; 1 (Box 37)
      - "Moi - Abracadada", undated; 1 (Box 37)
      - "Moi - Un auteur sous influence", undated; 1 (Box 37)
      - "Passage du Nord-Ouest, master", undated; 1 (Box 33, Item barcode 39002091246224)
      - "Le petit navire, 07", undated; 1 (Box 33, Item barcode 39002091246141)
      - "Petite fille Espitallier", undated; 1 (Box 37)
      - "Pierre qui roule...07", undated; 1 (Box 33, Item barcode 39002091246216)
        1' 02"
      - "La poésie est vanité + Raté! Assez!, master", 2006; 1 (Box 33, Item barcode 39002091246190)
      - "Quant au livre brouillon - DVD", 2004; 1 (Box 38)
      - "Quant au livre brouillon - machine à écrire version 2", 2004; 1 (Box 38)
      - "Raté! Assez! son", undated; 1 (Box 37)
      - "Rush Raté! Assez!", undated; 1 (Box 33, Item barcode 39002091246182)
        1' 30"
      - "Seulement", undated; 1 (Box 38)
      - [Software for movie], 2003; 1 (Box 38)
      - "Son film - original", undated; 1 (Box 38)
      - "Son film - copie", undated; 1 (Box 38)
      - "Son Quant au livre", container label "Son général du fond", undated; 1 (Box 38)
      - "Son séquence par séquence pour montage du film" CD-R grouping
        - "Son 1", undated; 1 (Box 38)
        - "Ligne de clip 2", undated; 1 (Box 38)
        - "Ligne de clip 3 - son", undated; 1 (Box 38)
        - "Ligne de clip 4", undated; 1 (Box 38)
        - "Ligne de clip 5", undated; 1 (Box 38)
        - "Ligne de clip 6", undated; 1 (Box 38)
        - [No media label], undated; 1 (Box 38)
      - "Sur la terre, le film, master", 2005 May 16; 1 (Box 33, Item barcode 39002091246208)
        5' 40" 6"
      - "Texte film Quant au livre", undated; 1 (Box 37)
      - "Vagues/Sibelius", undated; 1 (Box 38)
      - "Vanité de la poésie, master", 1996; 1 (Box 33, Item barcode 39002091246406)
      - "La vie nouvelle, La Vita Nuova", undated; 1 (Box 33, Item barcode 39002091246240)
      - "Voix de vieillard", undated; 1 (Box 38)
      - "Voix de vieillard", undated; 1 (Box 32)
      - "1ere prise de vue" MiniDV grouping
        - "Bory/film, livres dans la mer 24'19, original"", undated; 1 (Box 33, Item barcode 39002091246364)
        - "JFB DVD3", undated; 1 (Box 33, Item barcode 39002091246356)
        - "Caroline Deseilles", May 3; 1 (Box 33, Item barcode 39002091246349)
        - "Prise 4 Pest 7", undated; 1 (Box 33, Item barcode 39002091246331)
        - "Juliette Haubois séquence 3, le son, 0404", undated; 1 (Box 33, Item barcode 39002091246323)
        - "Mariana dernière prise, Gaby 1ère prise", undated; 1 (Box 33, Item barcode 39002091246315)
      - Unspecified MiniDV grouping
        - "2e séquence départ à 4'18" fin à 8'9"", undated; 1 (Box 33, Item barcode 39002091246398)
        - "Filmé le 25/06, Seulement (pour séquence Hitler)", undated; 1 (Box 33, Item barcode 39002091246372)
        - "Version 04/06/04 Machine à écrire version 2, Seulement 5'", 2004 June 4; 1 (Box 33, Item barcode 39002091246380)
      - Unspecified MiniDV grouping
        - "Les odeurs & Donguy livre animé", 2006 August 29; 1 (Box 33, Item barcode 39002091246281)
        - "Les odeurs, le goût Bons", 2004 August 29; 1 (Box 33, Item barcode 39002091246307)
        - "29/8 Bonne fin Donguy + fin", undated; 1 (Box 33, Item barcode 39002091246273)
        - "Générique (non) final", undated; 1 (Box 33, Item barcode 39002091246299)
        - "[?] mer 12", undated; 1 (Box 33, Item barcode 39002091246471)
        - "Hitler 9", undated; 1 (Box 33, Item barcode 39002091246463)
        - "Ligne de clips 4, ligne de clips 5, 4 pas bon, 4 bon", undated; 1 (Box 33, Item barcode 39002091246455)
        - "3 - 04' 02", undated; 1 (Box 33, Item barcode 39002091246489)
        - "La mer 4", undated; 1 (Box 33, Item barcode 39002091246497)
        - "Abracadada", undated; 1 (Box 33, Item barcode 39002091246505)
        - "Ligne de clip 1 avec son", undated; 1 (Box 33, Item barcode 39002091246448)
        - "Générique 1, début", undated; 1 (Box 33, Item barcode 39002091246414)
        - "Tout Au", 2004 August 15; 1 (Box 33, Item barcode 39002091246422)
        - "Copie ligne de clips", undated; 1 (Box 33, Item barcode 39002091246430)
  - Recordings, 1957-2012
    Audiovisual recordings are arranged chronologically, regardless of format. Undated items are listed alphabetically at the end of the subseries.
    Boxes 30-32 (audiovisual): Restricted fragile material. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
    Box 28 (records storage): Restricted fragile material. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
    Boxes 38-39 (computer media): Restricted fragile material. Reference copies of electronic files may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
    The subseries comprises tapes, cassettes, non-commercial DVDs and CDs recording sound poetry performances by Bory, conferences to which Bory participated, and other films directed by Bory. Also included are commercially-released record albums and audio discs by Bory and other poets.
    - "Des journées entières dans les virages", [1957]; 1 (Box 31, Item barcode 39002091246513)
    - "Poèmes sonores", 1974; 1; The audiotape is wrapped around the interior component of a reel. (Box 31, Item barcode 39002091246521)
    - Game Over, 1985; 1 (Box 28 (Record album storage), Folder 273)
    - La fabrication du crépuscule, 1985; 1 (Box 28 (Record album storage), Folder 274)
    - À l'impossible nul n'est tenu, 1985; 1 (Box 28 (Record album storage), Folder 275)
    - "Un auteur sous influence, lectures au C.I.P.M. Marseille en 1991 et 1998", undated; 1 (Box 38)
    - "Périgueux", 1993; 1 (Box 38)
    - Lecture au C.I.P.M. Marseille "Marseille - 3 déc 1993", 1 (Box 39)
    - Lecture au C.I.P.M. Marseille "Le refuge - 3 décembre 1993", 1 (Box 39)
    - Campos, Augusto de and Campos, Cid. Poesia é risco, 1995; 1 (Box 30)
    - Vanités, 1997; 2 (Box 30)
    - La fabrication du crépuscule, 1998; 1 (Box 30)
    - Game Over, 1998; 1 (Box 30)
    - Centre international de poésie Marseille. Cent titres, Poésie française de 1945 à aujourd'hui, [1999]; 1 (Box 30)
    - "Louis XV, par exemple", 199[9?]; 1 (Box 32)
    - Trois contre Un, 1999; 2 (Box 30)
    - Erratum #3, revue sonore / sound review, 2000; 1 (Box 30)
    - Ghérasim Luca par Ghérasim Luca, 2001; 1 (Box 30)
    - "Normandie, J.-F. Treilloux, La mer à la pointe de La Hague", 2002; 1 (Box 32)
    - "La vie sur terre 1", 2003; 1 (Box 32)
    - "La vie sur terre 2", 2003; 1 (Box 32)
    - "Dada & Cie", exhibit and reading at the Centre international de poésie Marseille (C.I.P.M.), 2005; 1 (Box 31)
    - "Le petit navire, Les proverbes 1", 2007; 1 (Box 39)
    - "Vierge / Menaces de Dachy", 2006; 1 (Box 32)
    - "Le futur a 100 ans, Hommage graphique au Futurisme par Ivan Messac", 2009; 1 (Box 39)
    - Jean-François Bory à la villa Buttafava, Contes et légendes d'or, 2009; 2 (Box 39)
    - Goldwriter, 2009; 1 (Box 39)
    - "Hommage à Francesco Conz: Shakespeare 8 Ko, Paris 2002-2010 - Hommage le 9 Juin 2010 à Vérone", 1 (Box 39)
    - "Hommage à Francesco Conz: Hommage à Conz, Vérone 9 juin 10 + archives Conz à Vérone 1992", 2010; 1 (Box 39)
    - Reading-performance at the École nationale des Beaux-Arts de Lyon, 2010-2011; 1 (Box 39)
    - "Louis XV, par exemple", 2012; 1 (Box 38)
    - "Inédit - t. beau poème de moi très rythmé avec en fond oiseaux puffin", undated; 1 (Box 32)
    - "Patate N° 2", undated; 1 (Box 30)
    - "Roman 1", undated; 1 (Box 32)
    - Roquin, Louis. Poème instrumental, undated; 1 (Box 30)
    - "Text und Aktionsabend", undated; 1 (Box 32)
- Photographic Works, 1974-2015; Series III; 0.25; 1 box + 2 oversize folders
  Published illustrations appear first in the series, followed by photographic postcards and prints.
  Series III contains photographic works created by Bory that relate to his poetic practice and that reflect his interest in collage, photomontage, and in the relation between text and image. Several pieces feature imagery of books and typewriters, a recurring theme in Bory's oeuvre. The series comprise magazine issues in which the photographs were published, as well as postcards and prints.
  See also: Series I. Writings, Jean-François Bory (Paris-Zurich: Hubschmid, 1974) (Box 5, Folder 41) for an artist's book composed entirely of photomontages.
  - "L'éternité: Numero monografico su Jean-François Bory", in Lotta Poetica no.47 -- published issue, 1975 (Box 20, Folder 195)
  - "Jean-François Bory", in L'art vivant no.47 -- published issue, 1974 (Box 26 (Oversize), Folder 264)
  - "Nourriture interdite", in arTitudes international no.39/44 -- published issue, 1977 (Box 20, Folder 196)
  - "Op.", in Delta - Revue internationale pour la poésie nouvelle no.39-40 -- published issues, 2014-2015 (Box 20, Folder 197)
  - "Poetry is dead" in Poema -- published issue, 2012 (Box 20, Folder 198)
  - "Sans titre" and "L'Éternité", 5 illustrations published in Les Lettres françaises, 2013 (Box 20, Folder 199)
  - Photographic postcards, undated (Box 20, Folder 200)
  - "Projets de cartes postales" photomontages -- prints, undated (Box 20, Folder 201)
  - Series of six photomontages -- prints, undated (Box 20, Folder 202)
  - Photographs of living statue with typewriter collage -- prints, undated (Box 26 (Oversize), Folder 265)
- Correspondence, 1972-2014; Series IV; 0.67; 2 boxes
  The correspondence is aggregated alphabetically by the first letter of correspondents' last names. A note for each file identifies all correspondents.
  Series IV. Correspondence, contains letters sent to Bory, with few or no copies of his replies. Largely of a professional nature, the correspondence documents other literary figures' and acquaintances' reactions to Bory's works and collaboration between them. The series contains a handful of letters from each of the one hundred or so correspondents. More substantial correspondence (five letters or more) is present for the following individuals: Marc Dachy, Jérôme Duwa, Bernard Heidsieck, Michèle Métail, Pierre Mréjen, Claude Royet-Journoud, and Sarenco.
  - "A", 1985-1988 (Box 21, Folder 203)
    Contains correspondence from: Angneroh, Marie-Thérèse; Arias-Misson, Alain.
  - "B", 1976-2006 (Box 21, Folder 204-205)
    Contains correspondence from: Baillieu, Jean-Marc; Ballet, Elisabeth; Barthes, Roland; Beck, Philippe; Benkemoun, Nicole; Bidaine, Philippe; Blaine, Julien; Blistène, Bernard; Borghesi, Graziella; Bourgois, Christian; Brisac, Genevieve; Bulatov, Dmitry.
  - "C", 1990-2007 (Box 21, Folder 206)
    Contains correspondence from: Carrega, Ugo; Cazal, Philippe; Ceccatty, René de; Chopin, Henri; Clair, Jean; Collomb, Isabelle; Courtade, Fabienne.
  - "D", 1982-2011 (Box 21, Folder 207-208)
    Contains correspondence from: Dachy, Marc; Dauriac, Jacqueline; Delaveau, Philippe; Delhommeau, Maëlle; Della Grazia, Paolo; Delouze, Marc; Delprat, Hélène; Deluy, Henri; Deseille, Caroline; Deyrolle, François-Marie; Di Crola, Gerardo; Di Manno, Yves; Dumas, Ph.; Duwa, Jérôme.
  - "E", 2001 (Box 21, Folder 209)
    Contains a letter from Espitallier, Jean-Michel.
  - "F", 1984-2007 (Box 21, Folder 210)
    Contains correspondence from: Fazzini, Gigliola; Fondazione Berardelli; Forest, Fred; Fourcade, Dominique; Frémon, Jean.
  - "G", 1986-2010 (Box 21, Folder 211)
    Contains correspondence from: Gaillard, Agathe; Galerie de Paris; Garnier, Pierre; Giraudon, Liliane; Grandmont, Dominique; Guilbert, Cécile.
  - "H", [1972]-2014 (Box 21, Folder 212-213)
    Contains correspondence from: Hagemeyer, Ines; Heidsieck, Bernard; Höch, Hannah; Hubaut, Joël.
  - "J", 1988-1999 (Box 21, Folder 214)
    Contains correspondence from: Jamme, Franck André; Jappe, Elisabeth; Jouanard, Gil; Jouffroy, Alain.
  - "K", 1992-1997 (Box 21, Folder 215)
    Contains correspondence from: Kames, Roman; Kostelanetz, Richard.
  - "L", 1972-2011 (Box 21, Folder 216)
    Contains correspondence from: Labelle-Rojoux, Arnaud; Lebel, Jean-Jacques; Leclerc, Françoise; Lemaire, Gérard-Georges; Lemaître, Maurice; Le Nautout, Manon; Lepage, Jacques; Le Sidaner, Jean-Marie; Lista, Giovanni; Lucot, Hubert.
  - "M", 1985-2003 (Box 22, Folder 217-219)
    Contains correspondence from: Marcos, Jean-Louis; Martel, Richard; Martini, Stelio Maria; Maunet, Isabelle; Mémoire, Danielle; Messac, Ivan; Métail, Michèle; Meyer, J.F.; Miccini, Eugenio; Mohr, Manfred; Mréjen, Pierre.
  - "N", 1977-1992 (Box 22, Folder 220)
    Contains correspondence from: Nannucci, Maurizio; Neveu, Angéline; Noël, Bernard; Noguez, Dominique; Nuridsany, Michel.
  - "P", 1974-2007 (Box 22, Folder 221)
    Contains correspondence from: Pane, Gina; Papp, Tibor; Parent, Beatrice; Perfetti, Michele; Peyrefitte, Alain; Picot, Marie-Laure; Pieyre de Mandiargues, André; Pignotti, Lamberto; Portugal, Anne; Puget, Sabine.
  - "Q", 1997-2006 (Box 22, Folder 222)
    Contains correspondence from: Quignard, Pascal; Quintane, Nathalie.
  - "R", 1979-2002 (Box 22, Folder 223)
    Contains correspondence from: Richter, Hans; Rogers, Elisabeth; Royet-Journoud, Claude; Rühm, Gerhard.
  - "S", 1984-2008 (Box 22, Folder 224)
    Contains correspondence from: Sabatier, Robert; Sackner, Ruth and Marvin; Sarenco (Isaia Mabellini); Seyvos, Florence.
  - "T", 1985-1986 (Box 22, Folder 225)
    Contains correspondence from: Talbot, Patrick; Tio Bellido, Ramon.
  - "V-Z", 1984-2001 (Box 22, Folder 226)
    Contains correspondence from: Veinstein, Alain; Viton, Jean-Jacques; Yves, [Dominique?]; Zweig, Ellen.
- Professional Papers, 1965-2013; Series V; 5; 5 boxes
  Organized into four subseries: Portraits of Bory, Reviews and Articles about Bory, Promotional Material and Event Publications, and Other Print Material.
  Series V. Professional Papers, traces Bory's career through promotional material, programs, and anthologies for exhibits, events, and performances to which he participated. Also included are reviews and articles written about Bory by other authors, as well as photographic portraits capturing him at work.
  Box 29 (audiovisual): Restricted fragile material. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
  - Portraits of Bory, 1981-2010
    - Photographs of Bory, 1981-2010 (Box 23, Folder 227-228)
    - Pen drawing with photo collage by Anne Slacik, 1990 (Box 23, Folder 229)
    - Pen drawing by Dominique Yves, 1993 (Box 23, Folder 230)
  - Articles about Bory, 1973-2011
    Arranged chronologically by publication date, apart from a group of clippings received as one file.
    - Reviews and news clippings, 1988-2011 (Box 23, Folder 231)
    - Lista, Giovanni. "Signification de Jean-François Bory", in arTitudes international no.4, 1973 (Box 23, Folder 232)
    - Bourgeade, Pierre. "Jean-François Bory ou l'ubiquité", in Opus international no.46, 1973 (Box 23, Folder 233)
    - Borer, Alain. "Jean-François Bory l'anarchiviste", in Opus international no.55, 1975 (Box 23, Folder 234)
    - Sarenco. "Jean-François Bory: poeta", in Lotta Poetica, 1983 (Box 23, Folder 235)
    - "Poésie s'honore", in Jazz Ensuite no.4, 1984 (Box 23, Folder 236)
    - Dachy, Marc. "Du livre comme création", in L'Infini, 1998 (Box 23, Folder 237)
    - "Jean-François Bory, Une angoisse transformiste", in Java, 2002 (Box 23, Folder 238)
    - "Dossier Jean-François Bory" in CCP, 2004 (Box 24, Folder 239)
    - Duwa, Jérôme. "L'Humidité ou la vie de l'avant-garde dans les années 70" in La revue des revues, 2005 (Box 24, Folder 240)
    - Duwa, Jérôme. Reviews in Action poétique, 2009, 2011 (Box 24, Folder 241)
    - Avila, Alin. "Jean-François Bory: soldat des mots", in Arearevues no.23, 2010 (Box 24, Folder 242)
    - Duwa, Jérôme. "Jean-François Bory: C.Q.D.F.", in La revue des revues no.47, 2012 (Box 24, Folder 243)
  - Promotional Material and Event Publications, 1965-2012
    Arranged chronologically and listed by document types and publication titles.
    - Posters, 1965-2012 (Box 27 (Oversize), Folder 267-272)
      Contains twenty promotional posters for events, exhibits, or publications; and four large size prints of visual poems: "Errata", "Hommage à Pavlov", and [untitled] by Bory, and [untitled] by Irine Schwartz.
    - Invitation cards and leaflets, 1975-2012 (Box 24, Folder 244-245)
    - Collected ephemera from exhibits and events, 1976-2008 (Box 24, Folder 246-247)
    - Désir d'Angéline Neveu revue parlée anthology, 1985 (Box 24, Folder 248)
    - C.I.P.M. Le Cahier du Refuge newsletter, 1991-2011 (Box 25, Folder 249-251)
      Contains issues no. 15, 38, 59, 91 109, 139, 162, 163, 191, 201, and 202.
    - Biennale internationale des poètes en Val-De-Marne programs, 1992-2000 (Box 25, Folder 252-253)
      Contains programs for the years 1992, 1993, 1999, and 2000.
    - Institut Français de Barcelone Répétition générale 1994 event anthology, 1995 (Box 25, Folder 254)
    - Rencontres du C.I.P.M: Poésie & autobiographie program and anthology, 2000; 2004 (Box 25, Folder 255)
    - Biennale de poésie visuelle France-Japon exhibit program, 2002 (Box 25, Folder 256)
    - Poésie Marseille
      - Event programs, 2007; 2009 (Box 25, Folder 257)
      - "Poésie Marseille 2007: extraits des lectures et des performances" -- accompanying media, 1 (Box 29, Folder 276)
      - "Poésie Marseille 2009: extraits des lectures et des performances" -- accompanying media, 1 (Box 29, Folder 277)
  - Other Print Material, 2006-2013